In this video, we're going to talk about our first parsing algorithm, recursive
在本视频中，我们将讨论我们的第一个解析算法-递归
descent parsing. So Recursive Descent is what is called a top-down parsing
下降解析。因此递归下降就是所谓的自上而下的解析
algorithm and you might suspect that there are also bottom-up algorithms and they are
算法，您可能会怀疑还有自下而上的算法，它们是
indeed such things but we will be talking about them later but in a top-down parsing
确实有这样的事情，但我们稍后将在自上而下的解析中讨论它们
algorithm, the parse tree is constructed from the top so starting with the root
算法中，解析树是从顶部构建的，因此从根开始
node and from left to right. And so the terminals then will be seen in the order
节点，并从左到右。这样就可以在顺序中看到终端
that they appear in the token string. So for example, if I have this token string
它们出现在令牌字符串中。例如，如果我有这个令牌字符串
here, this is a hypothetical parse tree that I could construct and the numbers
这里，这是一个假设的解析树，我可以构建它和数字
here correspond to the order in which the nodes of this parse tree are constructed.
这里对应于构造该解析树的节点的顺序。
So we have to begin at the roots, that's the first thing that happens and then if
所以我们必须从根开始，这是发生的第一件事，然后如果
T2 is a. Belongs here in the parse tree. That would be next thing that happened but
T2是一个。属于解析树中的这里。那将是下一件发生的事情，但是
then if we have a nonterminal of the next position, that will be number three and
那么如果我们有一个下一个位置的非终结点，那就是第三个，
then if it has children, well the left most one should be going left to right
那么如果它有孩子，那么最左边的应该是从左到右
will be the fourth thing to be generated. And then let's say the two children of
将是第四个要产生的东西。然后让我们假设这两个孩子
number four are both terminals that would be the next two terminals in the input and
第四个是两个端子，它们将是输入中的下两个端子，并且
so on. The next thing that'll happen is the second child of number three and then
等等。接下来会发生的事情是三号的第二个孩子，然后
the last two terminals appearing in left to right order. So let's consider this
最后两个端子按从左到右的顺序显示。所以让我们考虑一下这个
grammar for integer expressions and let's look at a particular input, a very simple
整数表达式的语法，让我们看一下特定的输入，一个非常简单的
one, just open paren five, close paren. And now, what we're going to do is we're
一，打开帕伦五号，合上帕伦。现在，我们要做的是
going to parse this using a recursive descent strategy. I'm not gonna actually
我们将使用递归下降策略对其进行解析。我不会真的
show you any pseudocode or anything like that. I'm just going to walk through how
给你看任何伪代码或类似的东西。我只想详细介绍一下
this, how this input string would be parsed. But using this grammar and the
这就是该输入字符串的解析方式。但是使用这个语法和
Recursive Descent Algorithm and the basic idea is that we begin with a nonterminal,
递归下降算法，其基本思想是我们从一个非终结点开始，
we begin with the root node and we always try the rules for nonterminal in order. So
我们从根节点开始，并且总是按顺序尝试非终结点的规则。所以
we will begin by starting with e goes to t and if that doesn't work, we'll try e goes
我们将从e转到t开始，如果不起作用，我们将尝试e转
to t + e. So, this is gonna be a top down algorithm beginning at the root. We're
到t+e。所以，这将是一个从根开始的自上而下的算法。我们是
gonna work from left to right, we try the productions in order and when the
从左到右工作，我们按顺序尝试制作，当
productions fail, we may have to do some back tracking in order to try alternative
生产失败了，我们可能不得不回溯一下，以便尝试替代方案。
productions. There are three parts. There's the grammar that we're using.
制作。包括三个部分。这就是我们正在使用的语法。
There is the parse tree that we're building and initially that's just the
这是我们正在构建的解析树，最初这只是
root of the parse tree 3e and finally there's the input that we're processing
解析树3e的根，最后是我们正在处理的输入
and we'll indicate our position in the input, how much of the input we have read
我们会指出我们在输入中的位置，我们已经阅读了多少输入
by this big fat red arrow and it always points to the next terminal symbol to be
在这个又大又粗的红色箭头旁边，它总是指向下一个端子符号
read, The next token to be read. So in this case, we're starting with an open
READ，要读取的下一个令牌。所以在这种情况下，我们从一个公开的
paren. Okay? And also in the grammar, you can see the highlighting here the brighter
帕伦。好吧?此外，在语法中，您可以看到这里的突出显示越亮
red color indicates which production we're going to try. So, we're going to begin to
红色表示我们要尝试哪种产品。所以，我们要开始
build our Parse Tree by trying production e goes to t, and what does that mean?
通过尝试乘积e到t来构建我们的解析树，这意味着什么呢？
Well, that means we make t the child of e and then we continue trying to build the
这意味着我们将t设为e的子级，然后继续尝试构建
Parse Tree. Well, so remember we're going left to right and top-down so now, t is an
解析树。记住我们从左到右，自上而下，所以现在，这是一个
unexpanded nonterminal, is the only unexpanded nonterminal so we have to work
未扩展的非终端，是唯一未扩展的非终端，所以我们必须工作
on it. And what are we going to do, well we're going to try a production for t and
这就去办。我们要做什么呢，我们要试一试t和t的生产
since we haven't tried any yet, we'll just try the first one, t goes to it. So the
既然我们还没有试过，我们就试第一个吧，那就试试吧。因此，
next step is to make nth a child with t and that's what our parse tree looks like.
下一步是使第n个孩子带有t，这就是我们的解析树的样子。
And now, we actually have something that we can check. We can check whether we're
现在，我们实际上有了可以检查的东西。我们可以检查我们是不是
making progress. So observe that as long as we're generating nonterminals, we don't
正在取得进展。所以请注意，只要我们生成非终结符，我们就不会
really know whether we're on the right track or not. We have no way to check
真正知道我们是否在正确的轨道上。我们没有办法检查
whether the nonterminals that we're generating are gonna produce the, the
不管我们正在生成的非终结符是否会产生
input string. But once we generate a terminal symbol, then we can compare that
输入字符串。但是一旦我们生成了终端符号，我们就可以比较
with the next input token to see if they're the same and in this case,
使用下一个输入令牌来查看它们是否相同，在这种情况下，
unfortunately they're not. So, the nth that we generated here doesn't match the
不幸的是，他们不是。所以，我们在这里生成的第n个与
open paren in the input and so clearly this parse, th is parsing strategy or
在输入中打开Paren，可以清楚地看到这个解析，这是解析策略或
this. Parse Tree that we're building isn't going to work out. So, what we're going to
这。我们正在构建的解析树是不会成功的。所以，我们要做的是
have to do is we're gonna have to back track. That means, we're gonna undo one or
我们要做的就是我们得走回头路。也就是说，我们要撤销一个或者
more of our decisions. We're gonna go back to our last decision point and see if
更多我们的决定。我们要回到最后一个决定点，看看是否
there's another alternative to try. So what's the last decision we made, well we
还有另一种选择可以尝试。那么我们最后做的决定是什么呢，嗯，我们
decide to use t goes to nth, so we can undo that and then we could try the next
决定使用t转到第n个，这样我们就可以撤销它，然后我们可以尝试下一个
production for t. And that happens to be t goes to n t so expand t using that
t的乘积，这恰好是t到n，所以用它来扩展t
production and now once again, we generated a terminal in the left most
生产，现在又一次，我们在最左边生成了一个终端
position and so now we're able to compare that with the input and once again
位置，所以现在我们可以将其与输入进行比较，然后再一次
unfortunately, the nth token does not match the open paren so we have to back
不幸的是，第n个令牌与打开的Paren不匹配，所以我们必须返回
track again. So we undo that decision. And this takes us back to trying alternatives
再来一次。所以我们撤销了那个决定。这就把我们带回了尝试替代方案
for t. There's one more possibility, and that's the t goes to (e). So we expand t
对于t，还有一种可能性，那就是t变成了(E)。所以我们扩展了
using that production. And now, we can compare the token open paren. With, is
使用那部作品。现在，我们可以比较令牌OPEN Paren。与，是
this open paren? With the open paren in the input and they match. And so, that's
这个空档的帕伦？在输入中有打开的Paren，它们是匹配的。所以，这就是
good. That means that we're, we might be on the right track. And since they match,
好的。这意味着我们可能走上了正确的道路。既然它们是匹配的，
anything that we do in the future is going to have to match the different input and
我们将来做的任何事情都必须与不同的输入相匹配
so we'll advance the input pointer. So now, where we're gonna work on next? Well,
因此，我们将使输入指针前进。那么现在，我们下一步要做什么呢？井,
we have to expand this non-terminal e and we're gonna do the same thing we did
我们必须扩展这个非终端e，并且我们要做我们曾经做过的同样的事情
before. We're just gonna start with the first production. So we have e goes to t
在此之前。我们就从第一部作品开始。所以我们有我们要去的地方
and then we have to work on t, so we're gonna pick the first production for t and
然后我们要制作t，所以我们要为t和t挑选第一部作品
we have t goes to int. So now, we can compare. Is int matching int in the input?
我们必须去国际机场。所以现在，我们可以比较一下。int是否与输入中的int匹配？
And if it does and so we advance the input pointer again, And now we're here and
如果它这样做了，那么我们再次前进输入指针，现在我们在这里
what's left, well we progressed to this point. We're looking at that open paren
剩下的，我们已经进行到这一步了。我们在看那个空旷的帕伦
and that also matches. So that matches the input and now we've matched everything in
这也符合。所以这与输入相匹配，现在我们已经匹配了
the parse tree and our input pointer is at the end of the string and so this is
解析树和我们的输入指针在字符串的末尾，所以这是
actually a successful parse of the input, of the input string. And so that means th
实际上是对输入字符串的成功解析。所以这意味着
at we accept and the parser terminates successfully.
在我们接受时，解析器成功终止。